bragg.com 2019-06-30

# Bragg Live Foods, Bragg Apple Cider Vinegar, Bragg Liquid Aminos,Systemic Enzymes, Bragg Live Organic Food Products, Patricia Bragg, Paul Bragg, Bragg Organic Olive Oil, Bragg Salad Dressings, Bragg Seasonings, Bragg Health Products

**Welcome to Bragg Live Food Product’s Privacy Policy**   
**  
Our commitment to your privacy:** ****To better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available on our homepage and at every point where personally identifiable information may be requested.  

The most common types of information we collect include things like: user-names, member names, email addresses, IP addresses, other contact details, survey responses, payment information such as payment details, transactional details, tax information, support queries, content you direct us to make available on our Sites (such as contest winners) and web analytics data. We will also collect personal information from job applications (such as, your CV, the application form itself, cover letter and interview notes).

**How we collect personal information**

We collect personal information directly when you provide it to us, and automatically as you navigate through the Sites.

We collect your personal information when you provide it to us when you complete membership registration and buy items on our Sites, subscribe to a newsletter, email list, submit feedback, enter a contest, fill out a survey, or send us a communication.

**Personal information  we collect about you from others**

Although we generally collect personal information directly from you, on occasion, we also collect certain categories of personal information about you from other sources. In particular:

  * financial and/or transaction details from payment providers located in the US, UK, EU, and Australia in order to process a transaction;
  * third party service providers (like Google, Facebook) who are located in the US or UK, which may provide information about you when you link, connect, or login to your account. The information varies and is controlled by that service provider or as authorized by you via your privacy settings at that service provider; and
  * other third party sources/ and or partners from Australia, US or UK,  whereby we receive additional information about you (to the extent permitted by applicable law), such as demographic data or fraud detection information, and combine it with information we have about you. For example, fraud warnings from service providers like identity verification service. 

**How we use personal information**

We will use your personal information:

To fulfil a contract, or take steps linked to a contract: in particular, in facilitating and processing transactions that take place on the Sites, like where you purchase an item from our company.  
Where this is necessary for purposes which are in our, or third parties, legitimate interests. These interests include:

  * operating the Sites;
  * providing you with services and information described on the Sites;
  * verifying your identity when you sign in to any of our Sites;
  * responding to support tickets, and helping facilitate the resolution of any disputes;
  * updating you with operational news and information about our Sites and services e.g. to notify you about changes to our Sites, website disruptions or security updates;
  * carrying out technical analysis to determine how to improve the Sites and services we provide;
  * monitoring activity on the Sites, e.g. to identify potential fraudulent activity and to ensure compliance with the user terms that apply to the Sites;
  * managing our relationship with you, e.g. by responding to your comments or queries submitted to us on the Sites or asking for your feedback or whether you want to participate in a survey or contest;
  * managing our legal and operational affairs (including, managing risks relating to content and fraud matters);
  * training Bragg staff about how to best serve our user community;
  * improving our products and services.
  * providing general administrative and performance functions and activities; and
  * processing your job application to Bragg.

**Where you give us consent:**

  * providing you with marketing information about products and services which we feel may interest you; and
  * customizing our services and websites, like advertising that appear on the Site – where this involves the use of cookies or similar technologies – in order to provide a more personalized experience.
  * For purposes which are required by law.
  * For the purpose of responding to requests by government, a court of law, or law enforcement authorities conducting an investigation.  

**What we do with your information:**

Any and all the information collected on this site will be kept strictly confidential   
and will not be sold, reused, rented, disclosed, or loaned! 

Any information you provide will be held with the utmost care and will not be used in   
ways that you have not consented to. 

**How we keep your personal information  secure**

We store personal information on secure servers that are managed by us and our service providers, and occasionally hard copy files that are kept in a secure location in the US. Personal information that we store or transmit is protected by security and access controls, including username and password authentication, two-factor authentication, and data encryption where appropriate.

**How you can access your personal information**

You can access some of the personal information that we collect about you by logging in to your account. You also have the right to make a request to access other personal information we hold about you and to request corrections of any errors in that data. You can also close the account you have with us for any of our Sites at any time. To make an access or correction request, contact our privacy champion using the contact details at the end of this policy.

**Marketing Choices  regarding your personal information**

Where we have your consent to do so (e.g. if you have subscribed to one of our e-mail lists or have indicated that you are interested in receiving offers or information from us), we send you marketing communications by email about products and services that we feel may be of interest to you. You can ‘opt-out’ of such communications if you would prefer not to receive them in the future by using the “unsubscribe” facility provided in the communication itself.

You also have choices about cookies, as described below. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. If you choose to reject cookies some parts of our Sites may not work properly in your case.

**Cookies (not the type you eat!) and web analytics**

When you visit our Sites, there’s certain information that’s recorded which is generally anonymous information and does not reveal your identity. If you’re logged into your account some of this information could be associated with your account. We’re talking about the following kinds of details:

  * your IP address or proxy server IP address’;
  * the domain name you requested;
  * the name of your internet service provider is sometimes captured depending on the configuration of your ISP connection;
  * the date and time of your visit to the website;
  * the length of your session;
  * the pages which you have accessed;
  * the number of times you access our site within any month;
  * the file URL you look at and information relating to it;
  * the website which referred you to our Sites; and
  * the operating system which your computer uses.

**Information you make public or give to others**

If you make your personal information available to other people, we can’t control or accept responsibility for the way they will use or manage that data. There are lots of ways that you can find yourself providing information to other people, like when you share information via social media. Before making your information publicly available or giving your information to anyone else, think carefully. 

**How long we keep your personal information**

We retain your personal information for as long as is necessary to provide the services to you and others, and to comply with our legal obligations. If you no longer want us to use your personal information or to provide you with Bragg services, you can request that we erase your personal information and close your Bragg webstore account. Please note that if you request the erasure of your personal information we will retain information from deleted accounts as necessary for our legitimate business interests, to comply with the law, prevent fraud, collect fees, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with investigations, enforce the terms of service and take other actions permitted by law. The information we retain will be handled in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**When we need to update this policy**

We will need to change this policy from time to time in order to make sure it stays up to date with the latest legal requirements and any changes to our privacy management practices.  
When we do change the policy, we’ll make sure to notify you about such changes, where required. A copy of the latest version of this policy will always be available on this page.

**How you can contact us**

If you have any questions about our privacy practices or the way in which we have been managing your personal information, please contact us:

**Call or write to us at:**

Bragg Live Foods, Inc.  
Box 7  
Santa Barbara, CA  
93102

**E-Mail:**  
General Information: [info@bragg.com](mailto:info@bragg.com)

**If you’re a user or visitor in the European Economic Area these rights also apply to you:**

For the purposes of applicable EU data protection law (including the General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (the “ **GDPR** ”), we are a ‘data controller’ of your personal information.

**How you can access your personal information**

You are also entitled to ask us to port your personal information (i.e. to transfer in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, to you), to erase it, or restrict its processing. You also have rights to object to some processing that is based on our legitimate interests, where we have asked for your consent to process your data, to withdraw this consent as more fully described below.

If you have unresolved concerns you also have the right to complain to data protection authorities. The relevant data protection authority will be the data protection authority of the country: (i) of your habitual residence; (ii) of your place of work; or (iii) in which you consider the alleged infringement has occurred.

**Both personal information and personal data have the same meaning in the context of this Privacy Policy.**

**Bragg Privacy Policy, effective date 25 May 2018**

**Corporate Address:**

Live Food Products  
199 Winchester Canyon Rd  
Goleta, CA, 93117
